<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on DataPlyr</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on DataPlyr</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2016 - 2017, Mcarrie; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 13:07:31 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Have Jupyter running on AWS even when you&#39;re not there!</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/04/22/aws-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 13:07:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/04/22/aws-post/</guid>
      <description>Setup Setting up a Jupyter notebook on an AWS ec2 instance to be able to run even when you close your laptop has to be one of the most useful tools ever! However, there&amp;rsquo;s not enough information online on how to do it.
From bits and pieces from all over the internet, here&amp;rsquo;s how you do it step by step..
Step 1: Setting up SSH Make sure you have an ssh key first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Chemistry?</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/04/21/basketball-chemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 13:47:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/04/21/basketball-chemistry/</guid>
      <description>Playoffs in the NBA just started, and I hear reporters on the news talking about chemistry all the time. However, what exactly is chemistry? What determines if teammates have good chemistry?
I decide to google &amp;ldquo;NBA Chemistry&amp;rdquo;, and the consensus online is &amp;ldquo;chemistry&amp;rdquo;, is actually really hard to define, because it is not quantified yet. So, how do you measure chemistry, when it could mean a million different variables. I decided to take a stab at it by using machine learning methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is the Murderer? (Exploratory Analysis)</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/04/20/firstkernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 21:49:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/04/20/firstkernel/</guid>
      <description>Below is my first exploratory analysis Kernel that I submitted on Kaggle.
First Kernel
Hello! I plan to look at solved murders. Eventually, I plan to make a prediction on the relationship of the perpetrator to the victim; however, this kernel I will explore perpetrator sex to the victim, the weapon used on the victim
import numpy as np import pandas as pd import seaborn as sns import matplotlib.pyplot as plt pd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Week at Metis</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/04/07/first_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/04/07/first_post/</guid>
      <description>Metis My first week as a student Data Scientist at Metis NYC has been challenging but also, incredible! I had high expectations coming in (after reading so many reviews); however, Metis has exceeded my expectations.
Since starting, my routine has been:
6:15 - 8:00 Wake up, Walk Dog, Do some coding
8:00 - 9:00 Take the LIRR to NYC
9:00 - 9:30 Do some code until lectures start
9:30 - 12 Lectures</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>